Abraham Murciano

Software Engineer

Personal Information

Ha-Va'ad ha-Le'umi St 21 abrahammurciano@gmail.com Jerusalem $+44\ 7397\ 842\ 936$

Israel +972 54 286 1293

GitHub https://github.com/abrahammurciano

LinkedIn https://linkedin.com/in/abraham-murciano-402952143



About Me

Passionate software engineer, full stack web developer, and IT technician offering 6 years of programming, maintenance, troubleshooting and repair experience combined with an aptitude for quickly adopting new skills. Hardworking and thorough with a passion for learning and gaining more experience in this field.

Skills

C/C++, Python, C#, Java, PHP, JavaScript, SQL, Prolog, Bash, Agena, LATEX Programming

UI Design HTML, CSS, WPF, XAML

Databases MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, SQLite

Other Linux, Object Oriented Programming, Agile, Git, Threading, Graphic Design

Professional Experience

2015-2018 Full Stack Web Developer - Freelance

> Designed sites to be compatible with top browsers, including Chrome, Firefox, and Safari, both on desktop and mobile.

> Used various technologies, including object oriented programming, PHP, JavaScript, and SQL to obtain optimal performance in websites.

Created site layout and user interface using **HTML** and **CSS** practices.

Hands-on experience using **Linux** and Apache web servers.

Summer 2018 Computer Technician - PC Clinic, Gibraltar

Systematically troubleshooted malfunctioning systems to identify and solve the problem.

Demonstrated professionalism and courtesy with customers while working to resolve complaints, problems or respond to questions.

2019 - 2021Computer Science Tutor - Freelance

> Taught less capable classmates and students from younger years material from various courses.

Demonstrated good communication skills in getting complex concepts and ideas across.

Removed and replaced malfunctioning components to correct hardware problems.

Education

2018-Present BSc in Computer Science, Jerusalem College of Technology, Israel.

Expected October 2021. Current GPA 89%

2011 - 2017Gibraltar Boys Secondary School, Gibraltar.

English: A*, Spanish: A*, Mathematics: A*, ICT: A*, Advanced Science: A, Science: A,

Hebrew: A, Judaism: A

Notable Open Source Projects

JCT Discord | A Discord bot to manage the Discord server of the English Speaking Program at JCT

Co-manged team of **eight** student volunteers.

Taught the less experienced team members to properly use Git.

Applied many **object oriented** principles.

Applied many python programming paradigms.

Designed and created a **PosgreSQL** database for the project.

Designed a very **modular** structure to ensure very **loose coupling** between different features of the project.

https://github.com/DenverCoder1/jct-discord-bot

rey-trace | Created a ray-tracing graphics engine in Java designed to produce realistic images given the

description of a scene.

Implemented a multi-threaded solution for optimal performance.

Practised working in an **Agile** environment.

https://github.com/abrahammurciano/rey-trace

Jack Compiler | A compiler for the educational object-based language Jack.

Wrote a multi-tier compiler from Jack to an intermediate language, then to assembly.

https://github.com/abrahammurciano/jack2hack

S Interpreter | Wrote an interpreter for the educational Turing-machine-like language S.

https://github.com/abrahammurciano/s-interpreter

Languages

English Fluent
Spanish Fluent
Hebrew Basic